Dwayne Lieck

Staufener Str. 32 | 79115 Freiburg im Breisgau | <u>dwayne.lieck@gmail.com</u> | +49 152 29351676 | <u>@dwayne_lieck</u> | <u>https://osf.io/v5npd/</u> | <u>https://orcid.org/0000-0001-9814-3488</u>

Profile

Dwayne Lieck is a researcher with a passion for improving psychological methods. To this end, he continues to work on multiple independent and collaborative psychology and metascience research projects. Dwayne is committed to inclusive and transparent science. In addition to implementing open science practices in his own research, he strives to advance Open Science through the development of community projects (e.g. <u>CRIC</u>) and involvement in Big Team Science (e.g. <u>SCORE</u>).

Education

Masters of Science in Psychology (Cognitive Psychology, Learning and Working)

October 2020 - April 2023

Masters Thesis: "Investigating Psychologists' Attitudes Toward Big Team Science"

Albert-Ludwigs-University Freiburg, Germany

Bachelor of Science in Psychology

September 2017 - August 2020

Bachelors Thesis: "The Unresponsive Climate-Bystanders: Why Don't They Help?"

Fresenius University of Applied Sciences Düsseldorf, Germany

Study of Philosophy and Law

October 2016 - August 2017

University of Bonn, Germany

Abitur (A-levels)

September 2009 - July 2016

Goethe-Gymnasium Düsseldorf, Germany

Research Experience

Research Consultant on the SCORE Project

May 2021 - November 2021

Claim extraction to facilitate reproductions and replications, improvements to claim extraction process

Supervisor: Prof. Andrew Tyner

Center for Open Science Charlottesville, Virgina, USA (Remote)

Research Internship in Metascience and Experimental Psychology

September 2021 - October 2021

Creation of a public list of team science projects, qualitative interviews with team science leads

Supervisor: Prof. Daniël Lakens

Technical University Eindhoven, Netherlands

Research Assistant in Intercultural and Social Psychology

November 2020 - February 2021

Experimental design, online-implementation of the experiment, data analysis

Supervisor: Prof. Philipp Jugert

DeZim Project Discrimination against Roma pupils in Germany, University Duisburg-Essen, Germany

Research Internship in Social, Occupational and Organizational Psychology

February 2020 - March 2020

Study design, literature review, translation of study materials

Supervisor: Dr. Jens Mazei

Technical University Dortmund, Germany

Research Intern in Intercultural and Social Psychology

July 2019 - September 2019

Meta-analytic coding, stimulus development, literature review

Supervisor: Dr. Sauro Civitillo

University Duisburg-Essen, Germany

Teaching Experience

Tutor - Scientific Thinking and Working

April 2022 - August 2022

Independent preparation and conducting of seminars, improvements to curriculum

Supervisor: Prof. Götz Fabry

Faculty for Medical Psychology, Albert-Ludwigs-University Freiburg, Germany

Tutor - Scientific Thinking and Working

April 2021 - August 2021

Independent preparation and conducting of seminars, supervision and evaluation of students' projects

Supervisor: Prof. Götz Fabry

Faculty for Medical Psychology, Albert-Ludwigs-University Freiburg, Germany

Publications

Primbs, M. A., Pennington, C. R., Lakens, D., Silan, M. A. A., **Lieck, D. S. N.**, Forscher, P. S., Buchanan, E. M., & Westwood, S. J. (Accepted/In press). Are Small Effects the Indispensable Foundation for a Cumulative Psychological Science? A Reply to Götz et al. (2022). *Perspectives on Psychological Science*. Open Access Version

Civitillo, S., Ialuna, F., **Lieck, D. S. N.**, & Jugert P. (2022). Do infrahumanization or affective prejudice drive teacher discrimination against Romani students? A conceptual replication of Bruneau et al. (2020) in Germany. Peace and Conflict: Journal of Peace Psychology. Open Access Version

Talks and Presentations

Lieck, D. S. N. (2021, June 24). *Introducing the Critique of Research Ideas Collective* [Presentation given at SIPS conference 2021]. Open Access Version

laluna, F., Civitillo, S., **Lieck, D. S. N.** & Jugert, J. (2021, February 2). *Infrahumanization and Affective Prejudice as Drivers of Teacher Discrimination Against Roma Students* [Poster presentation at InZentIM and TRIBES joint focal meeting 2021].

Open Science Projects

An Overview of Team Science Projects in the Social Behavioral Sciences

From September 2021

In collaboration with Prof. Daniël Lakens

First public resource with data on Team Science projects

ReproducibiliTea Freiburg

From January 2021

Organizer and moderator

Open Science Journal Club for faculty and students

Albert-Ludwigs-University Freiburg, Germany

Critique of Research Ideas Collective

From January 2021

Cofounder and Co-Organizer

In collaboration with Yvonne Oberholzer, Hannah Seidler and Prof. Thomas Rhys Evans

Community for early-stage peer critique on research ideas

Nowhere Lab

From December 2020

Assistant lab manager

Open community for researchers

Skills/Experience

Research Software

SPSS Statistics - Intermediate Knowledge

Programming and Statistics in R – Basic Knowledge

Statistics in JASP - Basic Knowledge

Statistics in Jamovi - Basic Knowledge

Statistics in PSPP - Basic Knowledge

Soscisurvey online studies

Unipark online studies

Research Skills

Scientific literature review

Creation, translation of study materials

Study supervision

Online study implementation

Meta-analytic coding

Conduction and analysis of qualitative interviews

Microsoft Office

Microsoft Powerpoint

Microsoft Word

Microsoft Excel

Languages

German - Native

English - Full Professional Proficiency

French - Basic Knowledge

Spanish - Basic Knowledge